Chashmeet Singh

2904 Donnelly St., Windsor, ON

(365) 228-1703 | singh1sy@uwindsor.ca | www.chashmeet.com | chashmeetsingh | chashmeet

Summary

- 4+ years experience as a Full Stack Freelance Developer in developing web and mobile applications
- Open Source software developer and maintainer of several repositories
- Interested in solving challeging tasks in an agile and fast learning environment
- Regular participant of local hackathons and technical meetups events

Technical Skills

Programming Languages / Frameworks (Intermediate): Swift, Ruby on Rails, C/C++, Java, Python/Django, JSP

Programming Languages / Frameworks (Novice): C#, Phoenix, PHP, Objective C

Operating Systems: Mac OSX, Linux, Windows

Software Applications: XCode, VSCode, Android Studio, Sketch, Rubymine, WebStorm

Databases: SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, PL/SQL, MongoDB

Education

Master of Applied Computing

Windsor, ON

University of Windsor

Sep. 2018 - Exp. Jan. 2020

Available for internship September 2019

B.Tech. Computer Science and Engineering

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

New Delhi, India

Aug. 2014 - Jul. 2018

Work Experience

SiliconBrane Inc.

Windsor, ON

Mobile App Developer

Nov. 2018 - Present

- Built an iOS app to receive and process data from IoT device using LoRa such as gps, device battery and direction
- · Created an algorithm to display location of the pet for the last week based on the current zoom

TechnoCab India Pvt. Ltd. Gurugram, India

Contract iOS Developer Jan. 2018

- Developed the iOS App for booking cab rides within a short span of 10 days to assist with the platform launch
- Integrated Google Maps and Places to find the starting and destination location and display on the map
- Was offered full-time employment based on the product's fast delivery and interaction with the other team members

Google Summer of Code Intern (FOSSASIA)

Singapore (Remote)

iOS Developer Intern

Rails / iOS Contract Developer

May. 2017 - Sep. 2017

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2017

- · Collaborated with a team of 10+ developers across the globe to develop and test the implementation of new features
- Presented weekly updates through demonstrations to other team members over Google Hangouts and scrum meeting
- · Held workshops in Delhi to promote open source software and taught usage of basic software development tools

Udacity Inc. Mountain View, CA (Remote)

Mentor / Reviewer Nov. 2016 - Aug. 2017

- · Mentored students across the world in problem solving and suggesting efficient ways of implementation
- · Reviewed projects of several students by providing quality feedback on the code structures and design

NXT Sports LLC Chicago, PA (Remote)

· Collaborated with a team of 6 people remotely across the world to develop the Web Application and the API

- Developed the iOS Application from scratch up within a span of two months by making use of the backend APIs
- Designed the frontend using Materialize CSS, hosted assets on Amazon's S3 and used SendGrid to send emails

CHASHMEET SINGH 1 March 11, 2019

Projects

FoodCourt (Team Project)

University of Windsor, Windsor, ON

Sep. 2018 - Nov. 2018

Tech Stack: Swift, Cocoapods, iOS, AutoLayout, Java, Springboot, REST API

- iOS app to enable users to buy products from multiple outlets in a food court in a single transaction.
- · Integrated authentication from OAuth libraries such as Google and Facebook.
- Developed Guest Mode to enable users to navigate through the app without signing up for it
- · Implemented Vendor side with listing orders dynamically from the server which gets updated automatically.

SUSI.AI iOS (Individual Project)

Mar. 2017 - Present

Tech Stack: Swift, Cocoapods, iOS, AutoLayout, Realm, Objective C, Java

- Designed a bot chat interface with the ability to show different types of messages like video, audio, maps, etc.
- Developed handsfree mode to enable the user to interact using hotword recognition similar to Siri or Ok Google.
- Built a feedback system to enable users to help improve the responses by the AI server.

GPS Info Alarm (Individual Project)

March 2018

Tech Stack: Swift, iOS, Cocoapods, AutoLayout, Realm

- Developed an app for a client to get GPS device alerts and alarms
- Integrated Google Maps and Places API to get the current location of those devices through alerts.

TrackMyShows (Team Project)

Sep. 2015 - Dec. 2016

Tech Stack: Android, Realm, Ruby on Rails, Java, SQLite, REST API

- Worked with Android to build the functionality to authenticate and locally save data of tv shows.
- Implemented the backend server to provide combined data to the android app from various other APIs.
- Designed the logic to provide synchronization between several devices owned by the user.
- After maintaining a successful 1k+ users daily and over 50k installs within 6 months, the app was sold for USD 2500.

Weekender (Team Project)

Apr 2016

Tech Stack: Android, Ruby on Rails, Java, SQLite, REST API

- Built at Yatra Hackathon within a period of 16 hours with fully functional API
- · Worked on the backend API to suggest nearby places for planning a trip with recommendations to places of visit

Honors and Activities

Mentor at Codementor.io	Oct 2015 - Present
Best Implementation of Security Measures - Hack Western V	Nov 2018
Mentor at Google Summer of Code	May 2018 - Aug 2018
Mentor at Google Code In	2017, 2018
Winner of Fastest Startup Time - Droidcon UK App, London	Nov 2016
Runner's Up - PayUMoney Hackathon	Sept 2015
Programming SIG Head	Feb 2015 - Jun 2015
Event Co-ordinator - Avensis (Annual College Techfest)	Sept 2014

Technical Training

IBM Cloud Essentials	Nov 2018
iOS Developer Nanodegree - Udacity	Sept 2016
Introduction to Linux - edX	Feb 2015
Introduction to Computer Science Using Python	Oct 2014
Introduction to Computer Programming	Sept 2014

March 11, 2019 CHASHMEET SINGH 2